And after
Speaker 1: the latest in the wildfires that are burning in California right now, fire officials releasing some new numbers about the damage from the boils fire. That's the one in Lake County. So far, 81 acres have destroyed 55 buildings and 80 vehicles. Containment remains at 50%. Firefighters are now monitoring for hotspots. This fire started Sunday in Clear Lake in a high risk zone.
Speaker 1: Nearby in Kelseyville, fire crews were able to control the Harbor Fire. It sparked on a Lake County hillside about 4:30 yesterday. It grew to about four acres. Evacuation orders have been lifted. No buildings were damaged. In Southern California, three fires are burning across the region. The largest is the bridge fire. It exploded in size overnight. It's now
nearly
Speaker 1: 48,000 acres, it spans from Los Angeles all the way into San Bernardino County. The blaze is threatening communities, forcing evacuations and burning structures. Last night, flames reached the popular Mountain High Ski Resort. It has burned some cheer lifts, there is currently no containment. And in San Bernardino County, a 34 year old man was arrested on suspicion of starting the line fire. This wildfire charred nearly 35,000 acres.
Speaker 1: 14% contained now. And
the USDA
Speaker 1: is announcing some new funding to combat future fire risks. Our Washington correspondent, Maddie Beertable, reports on this announcement and has reaction from California lawmakers. As thousands
Speaker 2: of acres in Southern California burn.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): We're announcing a commitment of $100 million. The USDA is
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): investing in new projects to reduce wildfire risk across the country.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): That will fund 21 projects in 18 national forests.
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): Agriculture Secretary Tom Vilsack announced the projects Tuesday. They span 14 states with
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): a focus on prescribed burns meant to reduce the fuels that make fires worse. California is getting the largest chunk of that money, 15 million in total for the El Dorado, Tahoe, and Sequoia National Forests.
We
Speaker 6: never lost a sequoia to fire for 1,200 years until 2017, and since then we've lost 20% of the sequoias.
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): California Congressman Scott Peters is trying to prevent forest fires with his own legislation. His bipartisan Fix Our Forest Act is set for a House vote later this month. He also has a bill to save sequoia trees.
Speaker 7: Help can't come soon enough. We have a tremendous challenge with wildfires. The
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): USDA money comes from the Inflation Reduction Act and Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill. But Secretary Vilsack.
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): says more will be needed.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Frankly, we need our friends in Congress to continue to provide the resources.
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): California Congressman Ro Khanna wants to do that.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): The wildfire issue
Speaker 8: isn't going away, especially with climate change as temperatures get hotter and the air is drier.
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): Khanna says people can feel the impacts, even far from the flames.
Speaker 8: It's really devastating. And there are times in Silicon Valley where we've gotten up and walked out and it's covered with smoke.